<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>Admin</author>
  <title>Is the M140i the best hot-hatch ever?</title>
  <description>BMWs very own rare wheel drive hatchback with a 3.0 inline 6 engine.</description>
  <content>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a hot hatch that&amp;rsquo;s posh and luxurious but also great fun on a twisty road, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.carwow.co.uk/bmw" data-interaction-section="body"&gt;BMW&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;M140i is a good shout, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re a keen driver. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite have the extreme looks of something like a Mercedes-AMG A35 but it compensates with a truly engaging driving experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You won&amp;rsquo;t immediately notice its performance credentials from behind the steering wheel, mind. While everything feels sturdy and well built, you certainly don&amp;rsquo;t get the same high-tech futuristic cabin that you&amp;rsquo;d get in a Mercedes-AMG A35. Nonetheless, the buttons in the BMW are easy to locate and use and the whole dashboard has a slight tilt towards the driver making it feel a bit like you&amp;rsquo;re sitting in a sports coupe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where the BMW M140i wins many points is it&amp;rsquo;s iDrive infotainment system that&amp;rsquo;s very easy to use thanks to a rotary-dial controller positioned near the gear lever so you rarely have to take your eyes off the road to operate its functions. Not only that but M140i models get BMW sat-nav as standard that&amp;rsquo;s really fast at picking a route for you or finding a detour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the M140i also gets rear seats that are quite cramped compared which alternative. If you go for a three-door model you have to squeeze yourself behind the front seats in order to get in, and while the five-door model resolves this, what remains is the fairly limited legroom and dark and dingy feeling you get due to the small rear and side windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of luggage space, the M140i is actually great thanks to a boot capacity that&amp;rsquo;s ahead of the Mercedes-AMG A35 and a lot of other alternatives. The rear seats also split-fold as standard so your M140i can cope even with a visit to IKEA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big reason why the BMW M140i has such a lovable character is that it has a comparatively huge engine for its class &amp;ndash; a 3.0-litre straight six petrol. As if the capacity wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, it&amp;rsquo;s also turbocharged to produce 340hp &amp;ndash; a fair bit more than the 306hp Mercedes-AMG A35. 0-62mph takes 4.6 seconds in the M140i, which is slightly quicker than the AMG A35, although that&amp;rsquo;s only in perfect conditions &amp;ndash; if it&amp;rsquo;s even the tiniest bit greasy, the Mercedes will probably be quicker thanks to its superior four-wheel-drive grip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other side of the coin is that the BMW M140i is hugely more enjoyable to drive in a series of fast corners when you compare it to just about any alternative. It&amp;rsquo;s playful without feeling scary and the linear power delivery of the big engine means that loss of grip is gradual and totally controllable. But, again, when it&amp;rsquo;s wet outside, you won&amp;rsquo;t be so quick and the four-wheel drive Mercedes-AMG A35 will inspire more confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out on the motorway, you never forget that the M140i is a sporty car &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s a lot stiffer over bumps compared with a regular 1 Series even with the adaptive dampers switched to their most relaxed setting but it&amp;rsquo;s never downright uncomfortable so you&amp;rsquo;re unlikely to be put off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the BMW M140i gets plenty of desirable equipment as standard such as the brilliant iDrive system, the fanciest driving aids are in the options list alongside other desirable kit such as a reversing camera. In fact, just a small detour through the options ends up adding thousands to your price so make sure to check out our&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.carwow.co.uk/bmw/m140i#deals" data-interaction-section="body"&gt;BMW M140i deals&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to see how much you could save after you&amp;rsquo;ve specced it to your taste.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2024-05-18 00:56:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2024-05-18 07:58:55</lastModified>
  <raters>0</raters>
  <rating>0</rating>
  <slug>is-the-m140i-the-best-hot-hatch-ever</slug>
  <tags />
  <comments>
    <comment id="987a5b4e-039a-4953-a3ce-28cbeaf23bbe" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True" spam="False" deleted="False">
      <date>2024-05-18 02:31:08</date>
      <author>Wiseman</author>
      <email>malukawiseman22@gmail.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>::1</ip>
      <moderatedby>Rule:authenticated</moderatedby>
      <avatar />
      <content>This is awesome.</content>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <categories>
    <category>e7fc0503-4ed2-45a2-9322-ccc26472cde5</category>
  </categories>
  <notifications />
</post>